# Luke Vella

# **Designer & Developer**

me@lukevella.com +49 1577 875 9286 Berlin, Germany

# Summary

I am a multidisciplinary developer with a passion for beautiful user interfaces and great user experiences. I've delivered multiple products to market, often overseeing projects from concept, through design and completion. My strong design background allows me to both communicate my thoughts effectively when working in a team but also work independently.

# **Work Experience**

#### **UI/UX Designer & Developer @ LOCK8**

Jun 2015 - Feb 2016

- Lead the design & development of a web based Fleet Management System.
- Set up workflows for development and deployment of the product across multiple environments.
- Redesigned lock8.me

#### iOS Developer @ Float.travel

Sep 2014 - May 2015

- Built an iOS application that offered free and paid walking tours.
- Developed a RESTful API that served content from a Wordpress site to the mobile application.
- Modularized the application to allow the production of a white label solution.

# Front-end Developer @ Zeepex

Jul 2012 - Dec 2014

- Built a single-page application that offered advanced search, data management and other tools that aimed to facilitate sourcing for recruiters.
- Developed an isomorphic javascript application that could intelligently discover social media profiles belonging to a person.
- Designed and developed zeepex.com

## Front-end Developer @ AWHPoker

Feb 2009 - Nov 2011

- Built and maintained a web application that allowed users to view information from the gaming network's back-office.
- Built a number of internal tools in the form of web applications and browser extensions.
- Redesigned multiple iterations of awhpoker.com

## Education

# **University of Malta**

Oct 2009 - Jun 2012

B.Sc. Computer Science & Artificial Intelligence

# **Expertise**

- Web Application Development
- iOS Development
- User Interface Design
- User Experience Design

## **Skills**

Javascript, ES6/ES7, HTML, CSS (SCSS), React + Flux, Angular, Backbone, Node.js, Webpack, Gulp, Express, Objective-C, Swift, Git, MySql, MongoDB, Heroku, AWS.

# **Side Projects**

# react-activity

2016

2015

<u>lukevella.com/react-activity</u>
Open source library of activity
indicators for react applications.

# Rallly

rallly.co

Open source collaborative scheduling application.

#### **Freeshot**

2013

<u>freeshotapp.com</u>
Dribbble client for iOS.

#### Links

LinkedIn: <u>lukevella</u>
Github: <u>lukevella</u>

- Dribbble: lukevella

- Twitter: imlukevella